# **Richard Eldridge**

Website: https://richardeld.com/

GitHub: https://github.com/Richardaeld | LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/richard-eldridge-4200221ab/

#### **Software Developer**

Software Developer with two years of daily coding experience. Equally comfortable in front-end or back-end development. Object-Oriented Program (OOP) language specializations include Python and JavaScript with additional skills in Django, Flask, MongoDB, HTML, and CSS. Excellent written and verbal communication skills, experience working in a collaborative team environment, and strong troubleshooting skills gained from multiple hackathons and previous employment.

# **TECHNICAL SKILLS:**

Technologies	Databases	Frameworks	Libraries	Version	Other
<ul><li>Python</li><li>JavaScript</li><li>HTML5</li><li>CSS3</li></ul>	<ul><li>MongoDB</li><li>PostgreSQL</li><li>SQLite</li></ul>	<ul><li>Django</li><li>Flask</li><li>Express.js</li></ul>	<ul><li>Bootstrap</li><li>React.js</li><li>Knex.js</li></ul>	Control     Git     GitHub	<ul> <li>Node.js</li> <li>Heroku</li> <li>Amazon Web Service (AWS)</li> <li>Object-Oriented Programming</li> <li>Google Searches</li> </ul>

#### **EDUCATION AND TRAINING:**

May 2020 - Nov. 2021 Code Institute - Software Development Diploma

\*EU Accredited RQF Level 5 Diploma

#### **PERSONAL PROJECTS:**

PERN project with RESTful API: DM Tool (front-end) | Repository (front-end) | Repository (API)

In-progress

A full-stack PERN project that allows users to view a plethora of DND content and allows authorized admins to control content. **Technology used**: PERN (PostgreSQL, Express.js, React, Node.js), Knex.js, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Github, Heroku, VSCode

## E-commerce Bookstore: Eldridge Music Book Emporium | Repository

Nov. 2021

A full-stack e-commerce bookstore application designed for users to search, rate, and purchase music books.

Technology used: Python, Django, PostgreSQL, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, GitHub, Heroku, AWS, Stripe, VSCode

# Recipe Compendium: Fat Raccoon | Repository

Jun. 2021

A full-stack recipe app with a colorful and intuitive UX that allows users to upload, view, edit, and share recipes.

Technology used: Python, Flask, MongoDB, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, GitHub, Heroku

## **HACKATHON PROJECTS:**

Smitten: Smitten | Repository

Feb. 2022

A front-end Valentine's Day themed game designed to entertain fans of the popular application Wordle.

• This project achieved 1st place in Code Institute's, "Love is in the Air" February 2022 Hackathon event.

My Contributions: JavaScript, CSS | My Role: Scrum Master, Lead JavaScript Debugger

# Wheelchair Accessibility Calculator App: Spinning Wheelchairs | Repository

Sept. 2021

A front-end project designed to determine if a hallway or doorway has adequate space for a wheelchair's turn radius.

This project achieved 3rd place in Code Institute's Trust in SODA 2021 Hackathon event.

My Contributions: JavaScript, HTML, CSS | My role: JavaScript Algebra Implementer

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE:**

# SGPS ShowRig, Inc., Norcross, GA

Feb. 2015 - Jun. 2020

Department Head of Motor and Power Control | Nov. 2019 – Jun. 2020

- Repaired and serviced motors and filed detailed tickets in a P.O.S. system. Delegated responsibilities. Power and Control Technician | Feb. 2018 – Nov. 2019
- Repaired and serviced electrical equipment and filed detailed tickets in a P.O.S. system.

Department Head of Rigging | Feb. 2015 - Feb. 2018

Learned two different P.O.S. systems and trained others. Delegated responsibilities.